SR. FULL STACK ENGINEER karlhillx@gmail.com | LinkedIn

SOFTWARE ENGINEER LOOKING FOR LEAD ROLES

SUMMARY

Full Stack Engineer/Architect with over 25 years of experience proven in executing the software development lifecycle (SDLC) in agile, consumer-facing environments. Subject matter expert in developing responsive, mobile-first solutions against aggressive project requirements. Built positive relationships across business functions to drive development.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER AT NASA, 2017 - Present, Science Systems and Applications, Inc. (SSAI), Greenbelt, MD

- Built an automated content registry application that crawls NASA domains to discover new online earth science content enriching internal data and increasing research efficiency by over 50%.
- Completely overhauled award-winning <u>earthobservatory.nasa.gov</u>, a high-traffic site with roughly 1.5 million monthly hits.
- Reduced save/load time by 20% with the redevelopment of internal administrative systems used by over 15 employees.
- Maintained four proprietary and third-party CMS systems and authored web services for distributing earth science content.

LARAVEL DEVELOPER, 2016 – 2017, InformedDNA, St. Petersburg, FL

- Rebuilt a case management application for medical professionals, resulting in better usability and reduced runtime performance by 50% of the previous application while saving roughly \$35K completing UX/UI work.
- Increased use with the new application by more than 35%; eliminated the need for three DB instances using custom APIs.
- Led development of features for the company's CRM system; successful adoption accelerated revenue by 25% in one year.
- Undertook major system upgrades for existing clients; provided 24x7 consulting support for 15+ clients.

SENIOR CONSULTANT, 2012 – 2015, Ticomix, Inc., Washington, DC

- Created custom SugarCRM PHP-based solutions from the ground-up in adherence to requirements for over 20 clients.
- Improved product quality for a top-tier client by reducing defect backlog from hundreds to 25 defects at launch.
- Implemented web applications for over 20 clients, including VDOT, Washington Redskins, and Kastle Systems.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, 2010 – 2012, Sabre Corporation, Bethesda, MD

- Developed and enhanced applications in a fast-paced environment, meeting performance and reliability for five of the largest global airline, hotel, and travel agency clients.
- Mentored five junior developers and new hires; aided in development leading to high performance ratings.
- Liaised with marketing to drive email and social media advertising efforts, using predictive modeling and clustering, resulting in a 35% increase in revenue.

Additional roles include **Senior Software Engineer** for **Verizon**, **Dante Inc**, **Visitar**, and **Advantage Industries**, plus current volunteer developer positions at **Friendship Place** and **The Renwick Gallery of the Smithsonian American Art Museum**.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Project Management - Rutgers University, Camden, NJ

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Computer Science coursework - University of Maryland Baltimore County, Baltimore, MD

Associate of Arts (A.A.), General Studies - Howard Community College, Columbia, MD

SKILLS

Laravel, PHP, PHPUnit, TDD, Apache, Tomcat, LAMP, MySQL, MariaDB, PostgreSQL, MVC, Symfony, Webpack, NPM, OOP, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, Vue.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Git, GitHub/GitLab, Subversion SVN, APIs, REST, JSON, UX/UI, Agile, Scrum, Java, JSF, SugarCRM, WordPress, Drupal, Apache Nutch, ElasticSearch, AWS (Amazon Web Services), Atlassian Suite: (JIRA, Confluence, Bitbucket), Composer, Bash & Shell scripting